Guide to the New York University Collection of Contemporary Composers' Websites MSS.496
Fales Library and Special Collections
- La Barbara, Joan, July 2017- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  The website documents her work as a composer and vocal performer. Her work is characterized by its exploration of the range of the human voice as an instrument. The website contains a biography of the artist, a list of her compositions, a discography of her published works, a calendar of her performances, a description of her works meant to accompany films, images of the artist, examples of her music in the form of embedded audio files, reviews of her work, La Barbara's resume and CV in the form of embedded PDF and Microsoft Word files, examples of her voice-over work, and links to videos of her performances. Capture of the site began in July 2017. This description is based on the July 2017 capture of the site.
- La Rose, Andrea, February 2014- ongoing; cuid5907; 3 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://reloadsanear.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Embedded Bandcamp audio files were not captured due to technological constraints.
  The website contains a biography of La Rose, and artist statement, information about her work as a composer, flutist, and educator, and blogs containing her written works, information about her flute method, and photographs. La Rose has been involved with many ensembles, both as a performer and composer, and specializes in chamber music and improvisational compositions. Capture of the site began in February 2014. This description is based on the June 2017 capture of the site.
- Lang, David, May 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://davidlangmusic.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Embedded Soundcloud audio files and some aspects of the site layout were not captured due to technological constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about his works and projects, articles written about Lang and his compositions, a discography of his albums, and a calendar of his events. The works featured on the site are classically-influenced opera, chamber, orchestra, and solo pieces. Capture of the site began in May 2014. This description is based on the October 2017 capture of the site.
- Lash, Hannah, July 2017- ongoing; 2 websites in 2 archived website.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://hannahlash.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Parts of the live site involving Javascript and Youtube were not captured due to technological constraints.
  The website documents Lash's work as a composer and performer of music for the harp as well as chamber, vocal, and orchestral groups. The website contains a biography of the artist, information about her works, examples of her solo performances on the harp in the form of embedded video files, a calendar of her events, links to news about and reviews of her works, and links to the websites of other composers and programs with whom she has worked. Capture of the site began in July 2017. This description is based on the July 2017 capture of the site.
- Latham, Clara Hunter, August 2017- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.claralatham.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Embedded Soundcloud audio files were not captured due to technological constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about her works and projects, articles written about Latham and her compositions, and examples of her music in the form of embedded audio and video files. The works featured on the site are classically-influenced but interdisciplinary, using traditional instruments and voice, and combining aspects of popular and experimental genres. Capture of the site began in August 2017. This description is based on the August 2017 capture of the site.
- Leach, Mary Jane, May 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.mjleach.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about her works and projects, articles written about Leach and her compositions, and examples of her music in the form of embedded audio and video files. The works featured on the site highlight Leach's use of non-traditional acoustics in her choral pieces. Capture of the site began in May 2014. This description is based on the October 2017 capture of the site.
- Lemmon, Eric, May 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://ericlemmon.net/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of violist and composer Eric Lemmon, information about his works and projects, articles written about Lemmon and his compositions, the composer's blog, and examples of his music in the form of embedded audio and video files. The classically-influenced works featured on the site primarily make use of traditional and electronic instruments, although they occasionally also feature voice and movement components. Capture of the site began in May 2014. This description is based on the October 2017 capture of the site.
- Leon, Tania, July 2017- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.tanialeon.com/index.html in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website documents the work of Tania Leon, a composer and conductor, whose works span the genres of opera, orchestra, and symphony music, incorporating vocals as well as instruments. The website contains a biography of the artist, news about her, information about her work as a composer and conductor, reviews of her work, interviews with the artist and examples of her work in the form of embedded video files, a discography of her published works, and links to purchase examples of her prose writings. Capture of the site began in July 2017. This description is based on the July 2017 capture of the site.
- Lerdahl, Fred, August 2017- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of https://www.fredlerdahl.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Embedded image files were not captured due to technological constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about his works and projects, including music and prose, and examples of his music in the form of embedded audio files. The works featured on the site are classically-influenced instrumental pieces for orchestra and chamber ensembles. Capture of the site began in August 2017. This description is based on the August 2017 capture of the site.
- Little, David T., August 2017- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://davidtlittle.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the composer and percussionist David T. Little, information about his works and projects, a calendar of his events, articles written about Little, and examples of his music in the form of embedded audio files. The works featured on the site are classically-influenced instrumental and choral pieces for small and large ensembles as well as solo performers. Capture of the site began in August 2017. This description is based on the August 2017 capture of the site.
- London, Frank, May 2017- ongoing; cuid5847; 3 websites in 1 archived website
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.franklondon.com/ and http://klezmatics.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  http://klezmatics.com/, an external site, was included due to its contextual value to the site that is the focus of this crawl.
  This is the archived website of New York City-based trumpeter, band leader, and composer Frank London. The website documents his professional work as a solo artist as well as a part of several music groups, including Frank London's Klezmer Brass All-Stars and Hasidic New Wave. Not only does the collection document London's contribution to both klezmer and world music, but the materials also demonstrate his deep interest in preserving Hungarian-Jewish culture. This description is based on the May 16, 2017 capture of the site.
- Lou, Michelle, April 2014-ongoing
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.michellelou.com/ order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Youtube, Vimeo, Instagram, and Soundcloud pages were also captured due to their contextual value to the site that is the focus of this crawl.
  This is a web art piece and professional website for composer and electronic musician Michelle Lou, structured as a web with interactive nodes, some of which link to external sites featuring several pieces of Lou's work and the artist's biography, performance listings, and others of which can be moved an manipulated. The videos linked to the website include performances of Lou's pieces "Different Furs," "In the Land of Milk and Honey," "Opal," and "Untitled Three Part Construction." Three of the nodes produce sine waves which can be played in combination to produce harmony or dissonance. This website was first captured in April of 2014, but has only existed in its current form since 2016. Prior to 2016, the URL was associated with a more conventional professional site for Michelle Lou featuring a biography, a selection of audio tracks, an events calendar of upcoming performances, and a now-defunct 'Random' section. This description is based on the November 2019 crawl of the site.
- Luck, Wendy, February 2014- ongoing; cuid5900; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://WendyLuck.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Youtube video and embedded audio files were not captured due to technological constraints.
  The website documents her work as a traveling performer and composer across several genres of entertainment, including music, comedy, and art. She is primarily a flutist, vocalist, composer, and multimedia artist. The website contains a biography of the artist, information about her works and examples of her musical and comedy works in the form of embedded audio and video files, images of the artist, and her blog. Capture of the site began in February 2014. This description is based on the June 2017 capture of the site.
- Maguire, Carl, February 2014- ongoing; cuid5856; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://carlmaguire.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website documents Maguire's work as a pianist, accordionist, band leader of the group Floriculture, and composer. The website contains a biography of the artist, information about Floriculture and its members, a calendar of their events, reviews of the group's performances, and examples of Floriculture's music in the form of embedded audio files. Floriculture exclusively plays Maguire's works, which combine precise scored playing with improvised sections. Capture of the site began in February 2014. This description is based on the May 2017 capture of the site.
- Maïda, Clara, April 2014-ongoing; 2 websites in 2 archived websites.
  This is the professional website of composer Clara Maïda. Maïda composes experimental instrumental, vocal, and electronic music. The site is available in English and French, and features a biography of the composer, a schedule of upcoming performances and events, a catalogue of compositions, a page with streaming audio samples of Maïda's work and PDF scores, links to press coverage of Maïda's work, the artist's writings and interviews, documentation of Maïda's scholarship including appearances at conferences and symposiums, information about Maïda's teaching, a bibliography of publications, a list of broadcast radio appearances, and galleries of photographs and visual work. This site was first captured in April 2014. This description is based on a capture in December 2019. English language versions of the older site are available, but the site was redesigned in 2018, and the English version of the website was added as a subdomain of the french version of the website. Updates to the site were largely aesthetic, and also included the removal of the 'Program Notes' page, the expansion of the 'Photos' page to include drawings and installation pieces under a new 'Visual Realizations' heading, and the additions of 'Writing' and 'Teaching' headings.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of claramaida.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
- MAPP International Productions, June 2017; cuid5935; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://mappinternational.org/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website details MAPP International Production's work in supporting contemporary artists in their performance art. The organization shut down on June 30, 2017. Capture of the website began in June 2017. This description is based on the June 2017 capture of the site.
- Marcus, Bunita, July 2017- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Marcus is a composer and performer on the bass clarinet and piano. She writes music for acoustic and electric instruments. The website contains a biography of the artist, reviews of her work, information about her teaching and compositions, links to buy her CDs, embedded image files of her scores, and Marcus' contact information. Capture of the site began in July 2017. This description is based on the July 2017 capture of the site.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.bunitamarcus.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
- Marshall, Ingram, February 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.ingrammarshall.net/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Embedded image files and Soundcloud audio files on the site were captured, but do not render in the archived copy. Future changes to the Wayback Machine may allow the files to be played.
  Custodial History
  This site used to exist at http://www.ingrammarshall.com/. The site moved to http://www.ingrammarshall.net/ in November 2017.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about his works and projects, a discography of his published albums, examples of his works in the form of embedded audio files, and articles written about Ingram and his works. The compositions featured on the site are influenced by Indonesian gamelan music and make use of electronic and traditional instruments. Site capture began in February 2014. This description is based on the November 2017 capture of the site.
- Matthusen, Paula, May 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.paulamatthusen.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about her works and projects, examples of her works in the form of embedded audio files, and articles written about Matthusen and her works. The compositions featured on the site make use of electronic and traditional instruments as well as everyday objects to create sound installations and music. Site capture began in May 2014. This description is based on the September 2017 capture of the site.
- Mattingly, Dylan, February 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://dylanmattingly.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about his compositions and projects, a calendar of his events, news relating to Mattingly, and examples of his works in the form of embedded video files. The compositions featured on the site highlight his work as a multi-instrumentalist and composer of new music. Capture of the site began in February 2014. This description is based on the December 2017 capture of the site.
- Mazzoli, Missy, August 2017- ongoing; 2 websites in 2 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.missymazzoli.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Calendar, embedded audio and image files were not captured due to technological constraints.
  The website contains a biography of composer and pianist Missy Mazzoli, information about her compositions and projects, a discography of her albums, articles and reviews about Mizzoli and her works, and examples of her music in the form of embedded audio and video files. The musical pieces featured on the site are classically-influenced opera, chamber, and orchestra compositions. Capture of the site began in August 2017. This description is based on the August 2017 capture of the site.
  The capture also includes the website for Victoire, a chamber and electronic ensemble founded by composer and pianist Missy Mazzoli. The site contains a biography of the ensemble and its members, a discography with purchase links for albums by Victoire, photo and video galleries, pages for news and upcoming performances, links to press coverage of the group. The site also features a link to a page on Mazzoli's website for 'Vespers for a New Dark Age', which was composed for Victoire, Laura Dune, and Glenn Klotche. Capture of the site began in December 2018. This description is based on a January 2020 capture of the site. The site has not changed significantly between 2018 and 2020.
- McKay, Dosia, February 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://dosiamckay.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Image, embedded Soundcloud audio, and embedded youtube video files on the site were captured, but do not render in the archived copy. Future changes to the Wayback Machine may allow the files to be played.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about her compositions and projects, articles and reviews about McKay and her works, McKay's blog, examples of her paintings, and examples of her music in the form of embedded audio and video files. The compositions featured on the site are instrumental, making use of electric and traditional instruments, influenced by classical and avant-garde styles. They are intended for performance by orchestra, chamber, and choral ensembles as well as solo performers. Capture of the site began in February 2014. This description is based on the September 2017 capture of the site.
- McKenna Lee, Andrew, May 2014- ongoing; cuid5865; 7 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.andrewmckennalee.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website documents his work as a composer and guitarist. The website contains a biography of the artist, a calendar of his events, news and press relating to the artist and his works, a catalog of his compositions and other projects, and a discography of his published works. McKenna Lee's style is influenced by classical, progressive rock, and psychedelic music, and he has played guitar in both solo performances and as a part of several ensembles. Capture of the site began in May 2014. This description is based on the June 2017 capture of the site.
- MELA Foundation, June 2017- ongoing; cuid5873; 12 websites in 1 archived website
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.melafoundation.org/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The MELA foundation features the works of Pandit Pran Nath, La Monte Young, Marian Zazeela, Jung Hee Choi, Charles Curtis, Terry Jennings, Angus Maclise, Richard Maxfield, Just Alap Raga Ensemble, The Theater of Eternal Music, and the Kirana Center Teaching Program, as well as some information about each artist. The website contains 1 embedded video file. Capture of the website began in June 2017. This description is based on the June 2017 capture of the site.
- Minakakis, Stratis, May 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.stratisminakakis.info/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Embedded image and Youtube video files on the site were captured, but do not render in the archived copy. Future changes to the Wayback Machine may allow the files to be played. Embedded audio files were not captured due to technological constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about his works and projects, examples of his works in the form of embedded audio and video files, and articles written about Minakakis and his works. The compositions featured on the site are classically-influenced and make use of traditional instruments and singers. They are primarily intended for ensemble performance, although some are for soloists. Site capture began in May 2014. This description is based on the October 2017 capture of the site.
- Mirza, Adam, July 2017- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.adammirza.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Mirza is a composer whose music is influenced by experimental jazz and new music. The website contains examples of his musical works in the form of embedded audio and video files, examples of his work as a freelance A/V recorder for other performers in the form of embedded audio and video files, a biography of the artist, and a pdf of his CV. Capture of the site began in July 2017. This description is based on the July 2017 capture of the site.
- Moe, Eric, May 2014- ongoing; cuid5862; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.ericmoe.net/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.